<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Dongsheng Deng&#39;s homepage</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Dongsheng Deng&#39;s homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Sublime Text 3 as LaTeX IDE</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-06/sublime-text-for-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-06/sublime-text-for-latex/</guid>
      <description>Sublime Text 是一个轻量级的、跨平台的编辑器，搭配 LaTeXTools 和 TeX Live 或者 MiKTeX 使用可以编译 TeX 文件。以前你可能会觉得 LaTeX 命令很难记得住，写起来很麻烦，但是借助 Sublime Text 里面的 LaTeXTools 插件你会觉得写 TeX 文档也可以是一种享受。从我自身的经验来看，自从配置好 Sublime Text 之后，我再没回去用 TeXworks 或者 WinEdt。
在 2014 年，我在自己博客上发布了如何使用 Sublime Text 搭建 LaTeX 编写环境，这么多年了，我的主页 发生了更迭，那篇帖子早已不见了，不过网上倒是能找到一些转载的内容。当时我将那篇帖子投稿到 LaTeX Studio，有兴趣的可以看下，传送门：Sublime Text 搭建 LaTeX 编写环境。时间过了这么多年，LaTeXTools 插件也发生了一些改变，原来的帖子感觉有点不合时代了，所以决定更新下。
Sublime Text 3 的界面图

2. 准备工作 首先，为了搭建 LaTeX 工作环境，你需要安装：
 TeX Live 或者 MiKTeX （本文以 TeX Live 2017 为例） Sublime Text 3 Package Control (Sublime Text 插件) LaTeXTools （Sublime Text 插件） SumatraPDF 阅读器（可选，用于预览 PDF）  在上述软件/插件安装之后，你需要把 TeX Live 的 bin 目录（D:\Program Files\texlive\2017\bin\win32）以及 SumatraPDF 的路径（C:\Program Files (x86)\SumatraPDF）添加到系统环境变量（PATH）中。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MongoDB unwind Operations</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-04/unwind-operation-in-mongodb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-04/unwind-operation-in-mongodb/</guid>
      <description>Just as the MongoDB manual pointed out:
 unwind deconstructs an array field from the input documents to output a document for each element. Each output document is the input document with the value of the array field replaced by the element.
 Here are two different cases in appliaction. It depends how the data is stored.
1. M array fields × N observations case If we have K variables in each document, and the M variables are stored as array field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configure Visual Stuido Code as LaTeX IDE</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-04/vs-code-for-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-04/vs-code-for-latex/</guid>
      <description>本文介绍如何配置 Visual Studio Code 作为 LaTeX 的编辑器。
1. 为什么用 Visual Studio Code Visual Studio Code（以下简称 VS Code） 是微软推出的一个编辑器，它的优点你可以百度一下，这里不赘述。对我来说，它最有吸引力的当属在 Windows 系统，它对于中英文字体的渲染。如果你原来用过其他编辑器，你就知道在普通屏幕上，中英文的显示效果简直是灾难。我原来因为编辑器的中文显示（当然还有 Terminal 的吸引力）一度想买 Mac，当然最后因为对性能和颜值的追求并不匹配我的财力，加上 Windows 上有些软件不能舍弃，最后作罢。
注：高分屏加上合适的字体，Sublime Text 的显示效果也非常好。
Visual Studio Code 的界面图

2. 准备工作 首先，为了搭建 LaTeX 工作环境，你需要安装：
 TeX Live 或者 MiKTeX （本文以 TeX Live 2017 为例） Visual Studio Code LaTeX Workshop （VS Code 插件） SumatraPDF 阅读器（可选，用于预览 PDF）  在上述软件/插件安装之后，你需要把 TeX Live 的 bin 目录（D:\Program Files\texlive\2017\bin\win32）以及 SumatraPDF 的路径（C:\Program Files (x86)\SumatraPDF）添加到系统环境变量（PATH）中。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Export from MongoDB to csv</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-04/export-from-mongodb-to-csv/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-04/export-from-mongodb-to-csv/</guid>
      <description>1. Use MongoDB to save json file When scraping data from web, the response may be json format, we can use json library to handle this.
import requests import json import pymongo # start pymongo connection = pymongo.MongoClient() data_base = connection.data_base collection = data_base.collection response = requests.post(url=url, data=payload, headers=headers) if response.status_code == 200: result_json = response.json() collection.insert(result_json)  If the json file is in right format, then you can use mongoexport command to export to csv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start MongoDB as service</title>
      <link>/posts/2018-04/start-mongodb-as-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/2018-04/start-mongodb-as-service/</guid>
      <description>1. start MongoDB normally Once you have installed MongoDB on your PC, you can start MongoDB using
mongod --dbpath C:\MongoDB\Server\3.6\data\db  2. start MongDB as service  remove the existing MongDB service intall the MongoDB as a service start the MongoDB service stop the MongoDB service  mongod --remove mongod --dbpath=C:\MongoDB\Server\3.6\data\db --logpath=C:\MongoDB\Server\3.6\logs\log.txt --install net start MongoDB net stop MongoDB  When you install or remove MongoDB service to or from you computer, you can add the --serviceName YourServiceName flag after the command to customize the service name as you wish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Note on A blogdown Tutorial</title>
      <link>/note/another-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/note/another-note/</guid>
      <description>I just discovered an awesome tutorial on blogdown written by Alison. I have to admit this is the best blogdown tutorial I have seen so far.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Quick Note on Two Beautiful Websites</title>
      <link>/note/a-quick-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/note/a-quick-note/</guid>
      <description>To me, the two most impressive websites based on blogdown are:
 Rob J Hyndman&amp;rsquo;s personal website. Live Free or Dichotomize by Lucy and Nick et al.  I&amp;rsquo;m sure there will be more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Hugo XMin</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>XMin is the first Hugo theme I have designed. The original reason that I wrote it was I needed a minimal example of Hugo themes when I was writing the blogdown book. Basically I wanted a simple theme that supports a navigation menu, a home page, other single pages, lists of pages, blog posts, categories, tags, and RSS. That is all. Nothing fancy. In terms of CSS and JavaScript, I really want to keep them minimal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Topics</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the board of research, here are some records of my research road.
Paper  Dongsheng Deng. Inflation policy under regime instability, 2012. (paper, slides) Dongsheng Deng, Rongwei Chu. Relationship between migrants’ remittance and life satisfaction, 2014. (paper) Zhao Chen, Dongsheng Deng. Risks and investor’s risk awareness in online P2P lending: evidence from transactions of lending platforms, 2017. (paper, slides)  Conference  The Third China Financial Forum, Shanghai University of Finance and Economics, Shanghai, November 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some Resources</title>
      <link>/resource/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resource/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the board of resource, here are some useful tools and tutorials.
Stata  Stata Learning Module Stata Class Notes  Python  DownloadHelper.py  LaTeX  ElegantLaTeX Book Templates: Designed by Dongsheng Deng and Liam Huang. Metropolis: A very beautiful and modern beamer theme. (Github, Download, Manual) LaTeX Beamer tutorial. (Beamer tutorial 2015, Beamer tutorial 2017) LaTeX graphic tutorial. (graphic tutorial)  Design  I designed the official logo of the Institute for Advanced Study of Wuhan University.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel and Photo Album</title>
      <link>/travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/travel/</guid>
      <description>Travel Records  Social practice of Wuhan University, July 2011, Suzhou, China. Summer camp of Fudan University, August 2012, Shanghai ,China. Ancient town of Xitang, March 2014, Jiaxing, Zhejiang, China. The Summer Palace, July 2015, Beijing, China. Visit friends and go sightseeing, Apirl 2017, Berlin, Germany. Sanya, *January 2018*，Hainan, China.  Photo Album  Graducation Year in Wuhan University (2013)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iFriend Links</title>
      <link>/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/links/</guid>
      <description>My Friends  My Blog: My blog website. Xin Ye: My undergradute roommate. Ph.D. candidate from the Department of Mathematics, Purdue University. Liam Huang: Coauthor of the ElegantLaTeX Note/Book Templates, programmer, TeXer. Murong Wang: Member of the ElegantLaTeX program, data scientist. LaTeX Studio: Palace for LaTeX user, maintained by ChinaTeX.  Tool Links  Everything: To locate files and folders by name instantly. Studio 3T: The best MongoDB GUI for me (Windows 10), free for non-commercial use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iFriend Links</title>
      <link>/postsx/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/postsx/</guid>
      <description> My Blog: My blog website. Xin Ye: My undergradute Roommate. Ph.D. candidate from the Department of Mathematics, Purdue University. Liam Huang: Coauthor of the ElegantLaTeX Note/Book Template, a programmer, TeXer. Murong Wang: Team Member of the ElegantLaTeX Program, data scientist.  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>